# Vy Nguyen

Web Developer | Grand Prairie, TX | vy.t.nguyen.11@gmail.com | 972-836-8522

# **Summary**

Natural problem solver and quick learner with high attention to details. Passionate about writing clean and efficient code, developing solutions, and learning new technologies. Experience with working in a fast pace environment and having strong time management skills, great communication skills, and a positive attitude.

## Skills

React . React Native . React Redux . AngularJS . JavaScript . jQuery . HTML5 . CSS3
Sass . Bootstrap . Reactstrap . Flexbox . Drupal . Wordpress . PHP . Node.js . MySQL
MongoDB . Loopback . Redis . Git . Github . Command Line Interface . Photoshop
Visual Studio Code . Xcode . Jira . Bitbucket . Teamwork . Asana

## Education

09/2017 - 04/2018

Origin Code Academy | San Diego, CA - Full Stack Web Developer Certification

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Redux, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Loopback, Redis, Command Line Interface, Git, and more

01/2008 - 05/2011

East Texas Baptist University | Marshall, TX - Bachelor of Arts in University Studies

Magna Cum Laude, 3.7 GPA Alpha Chi Honor Society & Dean's List with Honors

## **Portfolio**

Website: vunit.io Portfolio: vunit.io/portfolio Github: github.com/vunit2007

Code Challenges: codewars.com/users/vunit2007/completed\_solutions

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/vy-nguyen-715417102

# **Experience**

09/2019 to 01/2020

101 Network | La Jolla, CA - Web Developer

- Utilized Wordpress, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, & CSS.
- Developed responsive and dynamic Wordpress websites that ensured high traffic and user-friendly experience.

- Ensured cross-browser, cross-platform, and multiple device type compatibility for all web solutions.
- Supported operations team with day-to-day requests related to website functionality and performance.
- Involved in all aspects of the application development lifecycle: Idea, Development, QA,
   Documentation, Implementation, and Integration
- Developed, maintained, troubleshooted and enhanced existing web applications and services.
- Adhered to project schedules and effectively reported progress to meet challenging deadlines.
- Performed code reviews before merging into Github.

**Reason for Leaving & Hiatus**: Company had a major layoff and went out of business a few months later during Covid. California's strict and indefinite lockdown made it difficult to find work during the pandemic.

#### 10/2018 to 04/2019

### Tragic Media | San Diego, CA - Front-end Developer

- Took Photoshop files from design and created responsive landing pages using Angular 7, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Flexbox.
- Utilized Wordpress, Drupal, Filezilla, Photoshop, Git, Npm, and Gulp during the production process.
- Worked closely with other developers in researching, implementing, testing, debugging, deploying, and maintaining web applications.
- Completed tasks using teamwork.com for agile/scrum development methodology

**Reason for Leaving & Hiatus**: One of my projects got terminated and there was not sufficient work for me to do afterwards. Took a few months off to do independent studying before applying again.

#### 08/2018 to 09/2018

#### NewRocket | Vista, CA - Software Developer Intern

- Utilized AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Bootstrap.
- Helped troubleshoot widgets and service portals using the ServiceNow platform.

#### 03/2018 to 05/2018

#### Ficus | San Diego, CA - Software Developer Contractor

- Designed, built, tested, and deployed Ficus Mini, the beta edition to the gamified stock-trading Ficus app (available on iOS).
- Built the Ficus Mini app using React-Native for the front-end and MongoDB, Express, Redis, and Loopback for the backend.
- Utilized Xcode, Expo, and Photoshop.
- Completed tasks using Jira and BitBucket for agile/scrum development methodology.

### 02/2012 to 09/2017

# **AXA Advisors, Scottrade, JPMorgan Chase Bank** - Financial Professional

- Met with clients to discuss their short-term and long-term financial goals.
- Came up with solutions, strategies, and the right products to help clients achieve their financial objectives.